<!DOCTYPE resources [
<!ENTITY rsquo "&#8217;" >
    <!ENTITY nbsp "&#xA0;">
]>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name" translatable="false">Login_flash_screen</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open" translatable="false">Open Navigation Drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close" translatable="false">Close Navigation Drawer</string>
    <string name="this_month_s_content" translatable="false">This Month\'s Content</string>

    <string name="fp_w1_t1" translatable="false">
        <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Personal finance is all about managing your money and meeting your financial goals. Let us consider an example to understand this concept:&#xA0;</span></p>
        <p>&#xA0;</p>
        <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Consider a scenario where you receive a pocket money of 500 INR every week. Now, you are supposed to meet all your expenses such as buying stationary, spending it on friends birthday parties, dining out with your friends, etc within this amount of money. You found out that your old cricket bat is broken and you want to buy a new one worth RS. 2000. You decided to buy the Bat next month. There are two ways you can achieve your goal:&#xA0;</span></p>
        <p>&#xA0;</p>
        <ol>
            <li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Either you completely cut down all your expenses for the next month.&#xA0;</span></li>
        </ol>
        <p style="text-align: center;"><strong>Or</strong></p>
        <ol>
            <li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can start saving some part of your pocket money (30%) from this month itself in order to meet the requirement for the next month.&#xA0;</span></li>
        </ol>
        <p>&#xA0;</p>
        <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, in both the scenarios you will be able to buy the bat, but completely cutting down on your expenses would mean that you&#8217;ll not be well prepared for any emergency situation. What if you have to buy a textbook to prepare for your exams? What if you want to buy a gift for your best friend&#8217;s birthday? See, following the first method doesn&#8217;t prepare you for all these situations. Method 2 on the other hand will allow you to operate on 70% of your pocket money since you are already saving money from the previous month. Yes, you will have to cut down on some unnecessary expenses, you will have to plan your monthly expenses and this is what we call </span><strong>Financial planning.</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#xA0;</span></p>
        <p>&#xA0;</p>
        <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Planning your personal finances beforehand have several benefits such as, it makes you ready for an emergency situation, it prepares you for the ups and downs of the future. Some of the well known benefits of financial literacy are described in the chart below:&#xA0;</span></p>
    </string>

    <string name="fp_w1_t2" translatable="false">
        <p style="text-align: justify;">Financial planning also involves setting up personal financial goals that you want&#xA0; to achieve. To take control of the financial life one requires planning and that starts with setting goals. In this section we will discuss some of the ways in which you can set your financial goals.&#xA0;</p>
        <p style="text-align: justify;">&#xA0;</p>
        <p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #008000;"><strong>SMART Goals:</strong></span></p>
        <p style="text-align: justify;">&#xA0;</p>
        <p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">When it comes to setting goals, be it any life goal or financial goal, you can follow the SMART goal strategy. For any goal to be S.M.A.R.T it need to fulfill certain conditions that are as follows:</span></p>
        <p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">The goal must be Specific, Measurable, Attainable, Relevant and Time based. Before setting any goal you should judge it on these basis. </span><strong>For Ex:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Consider the above case where you wanted to buy a cricket bat, now let us analyse whether this goal is SMART or not. Let us begin by asking the following questions:&#xA0;</span></p>
        <ul>
        <li style="font-weight: 400; text-align: left;"><strong>Is it Specific?</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#xA0;</span></li>
        <ul>
        <li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">I want a cricket bat v/s I want a cricket bat worth RS 2000 next month as my old bat is broken. The latter is more specific and a better way to set well defined goals.&#xA0;</span></li>
        </ul>
        </ul>
    </string>

    <string name="fp_w1_t3" translatable="false">
        <p>&#xA0;</p>
        <ul>
        <li><strong>Is it Measurable?</strong>
        <ul>
        <li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Since you have to buy the bat next month, if you save 250 RS every week for 2 months, you will be able to buy it. If you can measure your progress this way, it will help you stay focused and motivated.&#xA0;</span></li>
        </ul>
        </li>
        </ul>
        <p>&#xA0;</p>
        <ul>
        <li><strong><strong>Is it Attainable and Relevant</strong></strong>
        <ul>
        <li><span style="font-weight: 400;">Is your goal attainable? Do you have the time, money and resources to achieve it? And is it relevant? Do you really need to buy a cricket bat or maybe you can play with your friend&#8217;s bat if you don&#8217;t play that often. Considering these questions will save you a lot of time, money and efforts.&#xA0;</span></li>
        </ul>
        </li>
        </ul>
        <p>&#xA0;</p>
        <ul>
        <li><strong><strong>Is your goal Time based?</strong></strong>
        <ul>
        <li>Time is money. Set deadlines for your goals and try to achieve it within the specified time.&#xA0;</li>
        </ul>
        </li>
        </ul>
        <p>&#xA0;</p>
        <p>&#xA0;</p>
        <p>&#xA0;</p>
        <p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><span style="color: #008000; text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Personal Finance Strategies:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">&#xA0;</span></span></span></p>
        <p>&#xA0;</p>
        <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The sooner you start financial planning the better it is. But it is never too late to create your financial goals to give yourself a sense of financial freedom. In this section we will discuss some of the strategies that will help you keep track of your goals.&#xA0;</span></p>
        <p>&#xA0;</p>
        <ol>
        <li><strong>Make a Budget: </strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">Budgeting helps you control your spending, track your expenses and increases your savings. It also helps you make better financial decisions, get out of debt, prepare for emergencies, and meet your long term financial goals. The 50/30/20 budgeting framework is a great example, it breaks down like this:</span></li>
        </ol>
    </string>


    <string name="fp_w1_t4" translatable="false">
      <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let us fit this framework in the above mentioned scenario of cricket bat:</span></p>
<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Maximum 50% of your pocket money goes towards meeting your essential requirements such as buying your stationary, commutation expenses, e.t.c&nbsp;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">30% of your pocket money will cover your lifestyle expenses such as dining out,attending birthday parties, e.t.c.&nbsp;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">And at least 20% of your pocket money you can save to buy a cricket bat.&nbsp;</span></li>
</ul>
<p>Just like the above example you can also create your own budgeting framework that fits your requirements and goals. Later in this module you will create your own budgeting framework that will help you achieve your financial goal.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Maintain your personal Savings Statement:&nbsp;</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your personal savings statement is nothing but a list of all your expenses and income. It helps to keep track of your expenses and maximise your savings. By comparing your current savings statement with the savings statement of your previous years, you can keep track of your financial progress. Your net expense minus your income will be your </span><strong>Net savings</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> for that period.</span><strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">&nbsp;</span></strong></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;</span></p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">&nbsp;&nbsp;<strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></span><strong>Net Savings =&nbsp; Income - Expenses</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Let us look at the savings statement of Joe, who is a college student,&nbsp; and estimate his net savings for this month:&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong>&nbsp;Joe&rsquo;s&nbsp; Savings Statement for the current month</strong></p>
    </string>


    <string name="fp_w1_t5" translatable="false">
        <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Maximise your savings by calculating your current savings and &nbsp; comparing it with that of previous months</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">&nbsp;</span></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Develop Saving Habits:</strong>&nbsp;&nbsp;The key to achieve your money goals is to build a collection of smaller everyday habits. Let us look at some of the smaller habits you can develop today that will eventually help you grow your money.</li>
</ul>
    </string>

    <string name="fp_w1_t6" translatable="false">

        <ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Reviewing your monthly bills can help you cut down on your unnecessary expenses</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Maximising your tax savings can help you repay your past debts</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">It&rsquo;s very important to set aside some money for unexpected expenses such as medical emergencies, a big car car repair, e.t.c.&nbsp;</span></li>
<li style="font-weight: 400;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Record everything that you purchase on a weekly basis so that you can look back on each expenditure.&nbsp;</span></li>
</ul>
    </string>

    <string name="fp_w1_t7" translatable="false">

<ul>
<li style="font-weight: 400;">
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Understanding your money personality is the first step towards financial health. We have listed down some of the extreme behaviours and the traits associated with them that people show when it comes to money. Most of the people don&rsquo;t exhibit these extremes most of the time, rather they have traits of each of these behaviours.&nbsp;</span></p>
<br />
<p><strong>Fun Activity:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Take the questionnaire given below to identify your money personality. Answer each question as per the instruction and at the end you will receive a score that will indicate which money personality best describes you.</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: center;"><strong><span style="color: #339966;"><a style="color: #339966;" href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1Nd4F30T5eEx1kjyFUx5MJkKPhdtMWDtMwrr4SQ90B1o/edit">Take the Money Personality Quiz Now!</a></span><span style="color: #339966;">&nbsp;</span>&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></p>

    </string>

    <string name="fp_w2_t1" translatable="false">

        <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Cash flow is nothing but movement of money </span><strong>in</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> and </span><strong>out</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"> of your wallet. Positive cash flow indicates your net worth is increasing. Let us look at some of the sources of inflow and outflow of money:</span></p>

    </string>

    <string name="fp_w2_t2" translatable="false">

       <p><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #339966;">Assets:</span></strong></p>
        <p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The sources that put money in your wallet are assets. These sources add to your income. </span><strong>Ex: </strong><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #993300;">The money kept in the bank is an asset since the bank pays you interest on that money. That interest adds to your cash inflow and hence it is an asset. </span></p>

    </string>

    <string name="fp_w2_t3" translatable="false">

    <p><span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #008000;"><strong>Liabilities:</strong></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The sources that take money out of your wallet are liabilities. These are the things that require additional cost of operation or maintenance. </span><strong>Ex:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #993300;"> When you have a car, you need fuel to drive it, it requires maintenance and insurance as well. Now the cost of all this&nbsp; is outflow of cash and hence the car is a liability.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #808080;"><strong>Difference between Assets &amp; Liabilities:</strong><strong>&nbsp;</strong></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Inorder to make the most out of your financial resources, one needs to know the fundamental difference between&nbsp; an asset and liability. Let us understand this difference with the help of a simple example.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p><strong>Ex:</strong> <span style="color: #993300;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Consider a scenario where you are the owner of a house. Now, that house can be an asset or a liability depending upon how much positive or negative cash flow is contributed by that property. It is explained in the diagram below:</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&nbsp;</span></span></p>

    </string>

    <string name="fp_w2_t4" translatable="false">

        <p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">In case I, the house is an asset since the rent received exceeds the mortgage and maintenance cost, hence contributing to a positive cashflow. However, the same house in case II is a liability since it contributes to a negative cashflow.&nbsp;</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #808080;"><strong>Types of Income Sources:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">&nbsp;</span></span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">There are mainly two types of income sources:&nbsp;</span></p>
<p style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</p>
<ul style="text-align: justify;">
<li><span style="color: #008000;"><strong>Active income sources: </strong></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">It is the hard earned money that one gets in exchange for performing a service. </span><strong>Ex:</strong><span style="color: #993300;"> <span style="font-weight: 400;">Salary from Job.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&nbsp;</span></span></li>
</ul>
<ul>
<li><span style="color: #008000;"><strong>Passive income sources:</strong></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> It is the money that requires little work or no active engagement to earn. </span><strong>Ex</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">: </span><span style="color: #993300;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Money earned via interest from the bank.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">&nbsp;</span></span></li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</p>
<p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">Financial freedom is a stage where you can meet all your expenses from the&nbsp;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">money generated by your passive sources of income. The more assets you&nbsp;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">accumulate, greater will be your passive income. This cycle is explained well in&nbsp;</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">the diagram below:</span></p>

    </string>

    <string name="fp_w2_t5" translatable="false">

        <p style="text-align: justify;"><span style="font-weight: 400;">One can increase his income from passive sources by investing the money earned via active sources. Let us learn more about investment in the next section.&nbsp;</span></p>

    </string>

    <string name="fp_w2_t6" translatable="false">
    <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Investment is basically an asset that is purchased with the intention that it will generate income at some point in future. When you buy a commodity as an investment, the intent is not to utilise that commodity, but rather wait for its value to go higher inorder to receive greater returns.&nbsp;</span></p>
    <p style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</p>
    <p><strong>Ex: </strong><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #993300;">Let say you bought 10gm of 24 carat pure gold today at a price of 50,000 INR and after 5 years the price of gold went high and you sold it for 60,000 INR, this would mean that you invested 50,000 Rs on gold and you got 10,000 Rs as a return on that investment after 5 years.&nbsp;</span></p>
    <p style="text-align: justify;"><br /><br /></p>
    <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Depending upon the type of returns, there are mainly two types of investments:&nbsp;</span></p>
    <p style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</p>
    <p><span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #008000;"><strong>Fixed Return Investments:</strong></span></p>
    <p>&nbsp;</p>
    <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These are the types of investments where the principal amount of investment is fixed and the interest rate you receive on that amount is also known and is fixed. Most common examples of these investments are:&nbsp;</span></p>
    <p style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</p>
    <ul>
        <li style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Fix Deposit:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">&nbsp;A FD is an investment offered by banks where you can deposit a lump sum of money for a specific&nbsp; period of time and the bank will offer you interest on that amount compounded annually. </span><strong>Ex:</strong><span style="font-weight: 400; color: #993300;"> If you deposit 1,00,000 Rs in FD for a tenure of 5 years at a rate of 5%, you will receive 1,27,000 Rs at the end of 5 years.&nbsp;</span></li>
    </ul>
    <p style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</p>
    <p>&nbsp;</p>
    <ul>
        <li><strong><strong>Recurring Deposit:&nbsp;&nbsp;</strong></strong>A RD is similar to FD except that in RD you can deposit a fixed amount of money each month and earn interest on it.&nbsp;</li>
    </ul>
    <p>&nbsp;</p>
    <p style="text-align: justify;"><br /><br /></p>
    <p><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>When to use:</strong></span>&nbsp;<span style="font-weight: 400;">The risk associated with these investments is low but at the same time the return rate is also on the lower side. They are beneficial when you want to invest your money for the short term and keep the money safe.&nbsp;</span></p>
    <p style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</p>
    <p><span style="text-decoration: underline; color: #008000;"><strong>Variable Return Investments:</strong></span></p>
    <p>&nbsp;</p>
    <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">These are the types of investments where the return rate is variable and depends upon the performance of the market.&nbsp;</span></p>
    <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Examples of these investments are:&nbsp;</span></p>
    <p style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</p>
    <p>&nbsp;</p>
    <ul>
        <li><strong><strong>Real Estate: </strong></strong>This involves purchase of land and property inorder to earn profit. Ex: <span style="color: #993300;">If you would have bought a plot for 1,00,000 Rs in 2015 the value of that plot in 2020 would be around 1,61,000 Rs considering a 10% rise in property prices every year.</span> Returns in real estate are mostly dependent on the development of the nearby area which is likely to happen in the long term.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>&nbsp;</p>
    <p style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</p>
    <p>&nbsp;</p>
    <ul>
        <li><strong><strong>Stocks:</strong> </strong>In order to understand stocks, consider a company called Dell. Now Dell is a company that manufactured Computers. In order to run their business, companies raise funds by issuing stocks which are nothing but shares that represent ownership of a fraction of a company. If a company issues 1000 stocks and you bought 500 stocks of that company, then you are the owner of 50% of that company. If you own 50% of the stocks in that company, that means you are entitled to 50% of the total profit that the company will make. At the same time if the company suffers any loss, you will have to bear 50% of that loss. That is why investing in stocks is risky but yields greater returns. Ex:<span style="color: #993300;"> Consider the case of Dell itself. The stock price of Dell in 2018 was around 40$ whereas its stock price in 2020 is around 60$. Which means that if you would have bought Dell stock in 2018 then you would have received a 50% return on that stock in 2020.&nbsp;</span></li>
    </ul>
    <p>&nbsp;</p>
    <p style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</p>
    <p>&nbsp;</p>
    <ul>
        <li><strong><strong>Mutual Fund: </strong></strong>To understand Mutual funds, one needs to understand that investing in stocks is tricky and requires expertise. Now, if you don&rsquo;t have expertise to analyse the market trends and you want to save your time, this is where mutual funds come into play. Mutual fund is a pool which collects money from different people who want to invest in any asset. The mutual fund manager, who has the required expertise in this field, then collects all the money and reinvest that money, on your behalf, in different investing opportunities. The profit gained by those investments is then redistributed to all the people who invested in the mutual fund. Some part of the profit is also kept by the fund manager as the management fees.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>&nbsp;</p>
    <p style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</p>
    <p><strong>When to use: </strong><span style="font-weight: 400;">The risk associated with these investments is high but the return </span> <span style="font-weight: 400;">rate is also on the higher side. They are most beneficial when you want to invest your money for a long term and willing to accept fluctuations.&nbsp;</span></p>
    <p style="text-align: justify;">&nbsp;</p>
    <p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Difference between fixed return and variable return investment will become more clear with the help of the table given below:&nbsp;</span></p>
    </string>
</resources>